JIMMY GRANADINO

Los Angeles, CA | (323) 868-1802 | jimmy.granadino@gmail.com

Portfolio: http://jimmygranadino.com
Github: http://github.com/jimmygranadino
LinkedIn: http://linkedin.com/in/jimmygranadino

SUMMARY

I'm an enthusiastic and analytical developer with an eye towards optimizing business functions. As an analyst by experience and a creative at heart, I research challenges and collaborate with finance, engineering and cross-functional teams to implement solutions for modern business problems.

SKILLS

JavaScript, Python, SQL, TypeScript, HTML, CSS, SASS, Java, jQuery, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, NoSQL, Express, Node.js, Django, React, Vue, RESTful APIs, Github, Agile, Data Analysis, Project Management, Financial Modeling, Analytics, Variance Analysis, Budget Forecasting, Snowflake, Tableau, Microsoft Excel, Microsoft Access, Adobe Photoshop

EXPERIENCE

USC Credit Union | Los Angeles, CA

Nov. 2019 – May 2020

Real Estate Associate

- Shifted the Real Estate department from a paper loan file process by implementing a paperless software solution and using department feedback in designing a fully digital workflow during the COVID-19 crisis.
- Lead training of seasoned Real Estate personnel and re-assigned employees on loan packaging product capabilities and best practices under short notice with an immediate directive of becoming Work From Home capable.
- Aggregated data for ad-hoc reporting purposes related to various metrics on a weekly, monthly and quarterly basis.

Blacksheep | Sydney, NSW

Dec. 2017 - Jul. 2018

Music Performance Residency

• Entertained patrons with carefully curated selection of music utilizing precise audio mixing and professional music production software while communicating safety needs to hospitality personnel on a weekly basis.

SmartBiz Loans | San Francisco, CA

Sep. 2016 - Jul. 2017

Relationship Manager

- Managed a multimillion dollar portfolio of SBA 7(a) loans while working directly with business owners from dozens of industries throughout the United States and maintained a judicious relationship with senior lending partners to engage in prudent lending.
- Compiled and underwrote challenging SBA 7(a) loan packages in accordance with SBA Standard Operating Procedures and loan underwriting criteria as prescribed by partnered banks.
- Exceeded \$1.1MM monthly volume goal on multiple occasions while receiving company recognition.

Bay Federal Credit Union | Santa Cruz, CA

Jul. 2015 - Sep. 2016

Financial Analyst

- Execution of technical and automation projects implemented organization-wide to eliminate hours of daily/weekly
 duties in various departments using SQL, VBA, and relevant programming languages or tools with database access.
- Analyzed general ledger accounts, communicate budget variances for business stakeholders, completed quarterly
 federal regulatory reports in partnership with Finance Manager, and produced monthly financial statements for
 board and senior leadership.
- Lead on reconciliation of multiple vendor platforms ensuring integrity of analytics, quantitative and liquidity models.

EDUCATION

General Assembly Aug. 2020

Software Engineering Immersive

University of California, Santa Cruz

Dec. 2014

Bachelors in Economics, Minor in Technology & Information Management